<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Stephen Lu</title>
	<atom:link href="https://2020.matrixmaster.me/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/</link>
	<description>&#34;The happiness of your life depends upon the quality of your thoughts&#34; — Marcus Aurelius</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 02:38:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/stephenzlu.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cropped-4733EC00-798E-4C42-8B88-7A722AC6F1A6.jpg?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Stephen Lu</title>
	<link>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">183885332</site>	<item>
		<title>My Room</title>
		<link>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/25/my-room/</link>
					<comments>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/25/my-room/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[thematrixmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 02:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://2020.matrixmaster.me/?p=114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you climb the twirly staircase to my room, you are greeted by the comfortable smell of fresh laundry and the relaxing sound of smooth jazz. Through the open door, you&#8217;ll first notice a baby-blue shelf carrying my most prized possessions: an antique stopwatch passed down from my grandfather, a Real Madrid jersey autographed by<a class="more-link" href="https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/25/my-room/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">"My Room"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As you climb the twirly staircase to my room, you are greeted by the comfortable smell of fresh laundry and the relaxing sound of smooth jazz.</p>



<p>Through the open door, you&#8217;ll first notice a baby-blue shelf carrying my most prized possessions: an antique stopwatch passed down from my grandfather, a Real Madrid jersey autographed by CR7, and a hardcover copy of Aldous Huxley&#8217;s <em>Brave New World</em>.</p>



<p>By the window, you&#8217;ll find a minimalistic desk supporting the weight of one laptop and countless piles of loose-leaf. From alphabetically sorted files to concisely written code, the computer epitomizes order and efficiency. Conversely, the paper is where you&#8217;ll find messy proofs in linear algebra, incomplete system diagrams, and randomly scattered motivational quotes like &#8220;<em>The happiness of your life depends upon the quality of your thoughts&#8221;—</em>Marcus Aurelius</p>



<p>Adorning the left-side of my room is a dark, elegant Yamaha piano that has accompanied me since the age of five. Hidden within this enigmatic instrument is a personal sanctuary where I can both find and create comfort. I play in hospitals when I volunteer. I play during after-school study breaks. Wherever I go, I can always find my piano and play.</p>



<p>Finally, nuzzled in the right corner of my room, you&#8217;ll be drawn in by a mosaic of photographs above my neatly-folded bed. One picture evokes my childhood addiction to Geronimo Stilton. Another captures my uncontainable joy on the podium of the national science fair. Together, they remind me to appreciate my journey.</p>



<p>So, what does your room look like?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1531637485122-60753ffac1b7?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1350&amp;q=80"/><figcaption>Source: Unsplash</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/25/my-room/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">114</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hunter Mentality</title>
		<link>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/24/hunter-mentality/</link>
					<comments>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/24/hunter-mentality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[thematrixmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 03:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://2020.matrixmaster.me/?p=100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On a cold wintry night, a young hunter quietly draws his bow and aims his last arrow at his prey. An accurate shot could guarantee his family&#8217;s survival during the harsh winter season, while a miss could endanger his newborn child&#8217;s life. It&#8217;s all or nothing. He closes one eye, holds his breath, and shoots!<a class="more-link" href="https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/24/hunter-mentality/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">"Hunter Mentality"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-justify">On a cold wintry night, a young hunter quietly draws his bow and aims his last arrow at his prey. An accurate shot could guarantee his family&#8217;s survival during the harsh winter season, while a miss could endanger his newborn child&#8217;s life.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">It&#8217;s all or nothing.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">He closes one eye, holds his breath, and shoots! The arrow whooshes through the air — fighting wind and snow. Maybe it hits, maybe it misses. Either way, it&#8217;s now out of his control.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">From a young age, I was conditioned by the hunter mentality — programmed by our outcome-driven society to adopt an all-or-nothing perspective towards my endeavours. As a competitive soccer player, I was taught that second place is just the first to lose. As a pianist, my parents insisted that playing one false-note could ruin my entire performance. Even now, as I apply to college, it is difficult to suppress the make-or-miss thoughts that arise during life&#8217;s momentous occasions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">While the hunter mentality can be a strong source of temporary motivation, my experience as a palliative-care volunteer at the Jewish General Hospital has shown me a different perspective.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">With the opportunity to assist medical professionals, I learnt the importance of asking <em>Why?</em>. “Why did you choose palliative-care?”, I would relentlessly ask every nurse and doctor. From the grief of personal loss to the desire of reducing pain, I was inspired to discover that those who sought deeper purpose were no longer bound by the hunter mentality. By asking <em>why?</em> they learned to prioritize quality over efficiency and comfort over cure. Ultimately, asking <em>why?</em> gave them greater motivation to find nuance in their actions and fulfillment in their endeavours. In a society where most matters are not black-or-white, I strive to perpetuate the questions that initiate deep, reflective thought — questions that make us human.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">By providing palliative-care, I met Sera — who taught me the value of journey. Sera’s end-of-life announcement was detrimental, but her inspiring commitment to rediscovering purpose in her journey ultimately erased the overwhelming shadow of her destination. As Sera’s health deteriorated, our conversations abounded with knowledge and vitality. I shared her giddy feelings when she met her husband in the halls of McGill. I felt her passion when she evoked her career as a preschool teacher. Faced with an outcome that she could not control, Sera found greater purpose to focus on her life — immortalizing her journey by passing down her knowledge to the next generation. From the people she loved to the lessons she learnt, Sera’s journey lives on with me — reminding me to value my own.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">My days as a JGH volunteer are now over, but the values of purpose and journey have stayed with me since — urging me to look beyond my hunter mentality.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">In my education, I learn to gain a deeper understanding of myself, and the world around me. As I study philosophy, data science, or health policy, I step in the shoes of Marcus Aurelius, Geoffrey Hinton, and Tommy Douglas. Through the crucial yet often overlooked journeys that led to their achievements, I strive to refine my values, my beliefs, and my character.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">This spirit brings me back to my communities — where I’ve found a profound sense of purpose in addressing systemic issues to enact sustainable change. In hospitals, I strive to humanize the patient journey through health-tech entrepreneurship. At school, I seek to reduce inequities by giving students equal access to resources. Although these initiatives might not ultimately succeed, I am motivated by the growth of my journey which will someday inspire others.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">Don’t get me wrong, there will always be a young hunter in me — driving my instinctive desire to achieve my goals. But I believe that every hunter who misses their prey should find their arrow, reevaluate their target, and shoot again.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-justify">Because for me, it is never all or nothing.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e5/Arash_Kamangir_Yazd.jpg/1352px-Arash_Kamangir_Yazd.jpg" alt=""/><figcaption>Statue of Arash Kamangir, a heroic archer figure of Iranian mythology</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://2020.matrixmaster.me/2021/01/24/hunter-mentality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">100</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
